(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T21:02:31.249126",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.
Maidens, seek Q.E.D.!
Question!! 知りたいな
Question! I want to know,
君はさ 僕のことどう思う？
what do you think of me?
Question!! ぼくはね、
Question! As for me,
君のこと… あとは宿題！
about you... that's homework!
ラブ・ラボ 引きこもっちゃんじゃ
Lab-lab, if you're a shut-in,
聞かなきゃってほら愛想
you've got to ask, see, affection!
論より証拠進んで 前進あるのみ！
Proof over theory, just press forward!
ねえ少し手伝って 人類の課題
Hey, give me a hand with mankind's task.
好き×好き×好き×好き×好き×好き＝？ 答え合わせしましょう
Like x6 = ? Let's check our answers.
見つけちゃお！魔法の公式
Let's find the magical formula!
化学反応してるよね ボクら
We're having a chemical reaction, right?
問題は まだまだまだまだ未解決
The problem is still totally unresolved.
恋の予感 物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね
Premonition of love—I'll just rewrite the laws of physics!
これぞ天才だ！ あの子より
This is genius! More than that girl,
その子より もっと「好きって」言ってちょうだい
more than anyone, tell me you love me!
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.
Maidens, seek Q.E.D.!
やっぱりさ さっきから僕のこと見てたよね？
Come on, you've been watching me, haven't you?
見てない？ じゃあ 僕が君のこと
You weren't? Well then, I'll make
どきまぎパラドックス
a flustered paradox out of you!
慌てちゃって隠れちゃう？
Panicking and hiding away?
宇宙も秘密主義じゃ ビッグバン！
If the universe is secretive too—Big Bang!
ねえ 君とふたり 人類の終わり
Hey, just the two of us at the end of humanity,
好き×好き×好き×好き×好き×好き＝？ 無限大未来でしょ？
Like x6 = ? It's an infinite future, right?
解きましましょう！
Let's solve it!
魔法の公式 惹かれ合うたび
Every time we're drawn by the magic formula,
不思議なレポートは 進行形
our mysterious report is in progress.
DNA連載中！ 君の細胞 書き換えちゃうもんね
DNA in serialization! I'll rewrite your cells!
まさに天才だ！ あの子より
Truly a genius! More than that girl,
その子より ずっと「好きって」言ってるじゃん！
more than anyone, you keep saying you love me!
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.
Maidens, seek Q.E.D.!
ねぇ僕らふたり 人類の終わりに 割り切れなかったあまりだったら
Hey, if the two of us at humanity's end are just an unresolvable remainder,
ねえ少し手伝って 人類の課題
Hey, give me a hand with mankind's task.
好き×好き×好き×好き×好き×好き＝？ 答え合わせしましょう
Like x6 = ? Let's check our answers.
見つけちゃお！魔法の公式 化学反応してるよね ボクら
Let's find the magical formula! We're having a chemical reaction, right?
問題は まだまだまだまだ未解決
The problem is still totally unresolved.
恋の予感 物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね
Premonition of love—I'll just rewrite the laws of physics!
これぞ 天才だ！
This is true genius!
あの子より
Than that girl,
その子より
than that other girl,
もっと「好き」って言ってちょうだい
please say you love me even more!
求めよ求めよ Q.E.D.！！
Seek and you shall find, Q.E.D.!!
3.14159265358979323846264338327950288419
Q.E.D.！！
Q.E.D.!!
はーい、みなさん！こんこよー！
Hi everyone! Konkoyo!
ホロライブ6期生、ホロックスの頭脳！博衣こよりだよー！
Hololive 6th Generation, Holox's brains! Hakui Koyori here!
今日は、こよの生誕ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Koyori's birthday live today!
お誕生日おめでとうのコメントもいっぱいいがとう！
And thank you so much for all the happy birthday comments!
まず1曲目は、一周年にてお披露目した7星降誕学団さんに作っていただいたオリジナル曲、「乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.」から始めさせていただきました！
First, we started with my original song "Otome yo Motomeyo Q.E.D.", created for me by Nanahoshi Kangenrakudan to celebrate my 1st anniversary!
ダンスも、みんな、この曲、どうでしたか？
How did everyone like the dance and the song?
そして、見てください！てでーん！今回は、ライブ用にめっっっちゃ可愛いステージを作っちゃいました！
And look! Ta-da! This time, I made a super-duper cute stage just for this live!
お誕生日ケーキもドどん！とありますし、なんと、こよの大好きなドットも使っていたりして、めちゃめちゃ素敵じゃないですか？
There's a giant birthday cake, and I even used my favorite pixel art touches—isn't it just so wonderful?
さて、このステージで行う今回のライブは、サブタイトルに「メモリー」とついているように、デビューしてから今日までの思い出の一部を曲と一緒に振り返る、というテーマで作りました！
Now, for this live on this stage, with the subtitle "Memory", we made it with the theme of looking back at some of our memories from debut until today together with songs!
こよとみんなとの思い出、そしてゲストの皆さんとの思い出を、歌と演出でたくさん詰め込みましたので、ぜひ最後の瞬間まで見ていってくださいね！
I've packed so many memories with Koyori and everyone, and with all our guest friends, into the songs and staging, so please be sure to watch until the very last moment!
それでは！ゲストパート一発目！早速いっちゃおー！
And now! For our very first guest part! Let's get right into it!
2022年にこの作品と出会えた思い出とともに、大好きな先輩とアイドルしちゃいます！
Together with the memories of meeting this work in 2022, I'm going to idolize with my beloved seniors!
I say...
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
うぶ毛の小鳥たちも
Even newborn baby birds
いつか空に羽ばたき
will someday soar through the sky,
大きな強い翼で飛ぶ
flying on great, strong wings.
諦めちゃダメなんだ
Don't ever give up,
その日が絶対来る
that day will definitely come.
君も感じてるよね
You can feel it too, can't you?
始まりの鼓動
The pulse of the beginning.
明日へ変われ！
Change towards tomorrow!
希望に変われ！
Transform into hope!
眩しい光に照らされて変われ START!!
Illuminated by brilliant light, change and START!!
悲しみに閉じ込められて
Shut away in sadness,
泣くだけの君じゃない
you aren't someone who just cries.
熱い胸きっと未来を切り開く筈さ
With a burning heart, you'll surely carve out the future!
悲しみに閉じ込められて
Shut away in sadness,
泣くだけじゃつまらない
just crying is no fun at all.
きっと (きっと)
I'm sure (I'm sure)
君の (夢の)
your (dream's)
力 (今を) 動かす力
power (right now) that moves things—
信じているよ… だから START!!
I believe in it... so START!!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
雨上がりの気分で
In a mood like after the rain,
高まる期待のなか
amidst mounting expectations,
頷いたことさえも思い出にしよう
let's turn even our nods into memories.
明日が咲くよ！
Tomorrow will blossom!
希望が咲くよ！
Hope will blossom!
楽しいメロディー口ずさみ咲いた DASH!!
Humming a cheerful melody, it blossomed, DASH!!
喜びを受け止めて 君と僕つながろう
Embracing the joy, you and I will connect.
迷い道やっと思いきり抜け出した筈さ
We've surely broken free from the maze at last.
喜びを受け止めて 君と僕進もうだろう
Embracing the joy, you and I will push forward.
それは (それは) 遠い (夢の) カケラ (だけど) 愛しいカケラ
Those are (those are) distant (dream's) fragments (but) precious fragments,
彼方へと… 僕は DASH!!
towards the other side... I'll DASH!!
I say...
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
うぶ毛の小鳥たちも
Even newborn baby birds
いつか空に羽ばたく
will someday soar through the sky,
大きな強い翼で飛ぶ
flying with big, strong wings.
諦めちゃダメなんだ
Don't ever give up,
その日が絶対来る
that day will definitely come.
君も感じてるでしょ
You can feel it too, can't you?
始まりの鼓動
The heartbeat of the beginning.
明日よ変われ!
Tomorrow, change!
希望に変われ!
Turn into hope!
眩しい光に照らされて変われSTART!!
Shining in bright light, start!
悲しみに閉じ込められて
Trapped in sorrow,
泣くだけの君じゃない
you aren't one to just cry.
熱い胸きっと未来を切り開く筈さ
Your blazing heart will surely carve open the future.
悲しみに閉じ込められて
Trapped in sorrow,
泣くだけじゃつまらない
just crying is no fun.
きっと(きっと)君の(夢の)
I'm sure your dream's
チカラ(今を)動かすチカラ
power can set the present in motion.
信じてるよ...だから START!!
I believe in you... so start!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
喜びを受け止めて
Accepting the joy,
君と僕つなごうよ
let's connect, you and me.
迷い道やっと外へ抜け出した筈さ
We've surely broken out of the maze at last.
喜びを受け止めて
Accepting the joy,
君と僕進むだろう
we will push forward, you and me.
それは(それは)遠い(夢の)
Those are distant fragments,
カケラ(だけど)愛しいカケラ
yet precious fragments of dreams.
彼方へと...僕は DASH!!
Towards the beyond... I'll dash!
Hey, hey, hey, START:DASH!!
自分が自分の事を愛して
Loving oneself,
何が悪いのか?嫉妬でしょうか?
what's wrong with that? Is it jealousy?
痛いだとか変わってるだとか
Calling me cringe or weird,
届きませんね そのリプライ
I can't hear those replies at all.
大好きななお洋服 大好きなお化粧で
In my favorite clothes and favorite makeup,
お決まりのハートツイン巻いて
with my signature curled twin-tails,
お出かけしよう 日傘持って
let's go out with a parasol.
ぼっちだって幸せだもん
Even being alone, I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cunning.
気になっちゃうよね?ごめん
Does it bother you? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for trying hard.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for my high girlish charm.
ムカついしちゃうよね?ざまぁw
Does it piss you off? Too bad!
貴方は貴方事だけどさぁ
You should mind your own business,
私に干渉しないでください
and please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけれど
They say birds of a feather flock together,
届きませんね その陰口
but I can't hear those gossips at all.
重い厚底ブーツ お気に入りのリュックで
In heavy thick boots and my favorite backpack,
崩せない前髪櫛刺してて
combing my unyielding bangs,
お出かけしよう 軽い女?ふざけんな
let's go out. An easy woman? No way!
重すぎるつーの
That's way too heavy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
この時代生きててごめん
Sorry for living in this era.
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out.
意識しちゃうよね?ごめん
You notice it, don't you? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
自分磨きしてごめん
Sorry for polishing myself.
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for acting coquette.
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for captivating you.
ムカついしちゃうでしょ?ざまぁw
Does it piss you off? Too bad!
趣味の違い 変わり者と
Different hobbies, called an eccentric,
曲げたくない 怖くもない
I won't bend, nor am I afraid.
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want to be my own ally,
一番大切にしてあげたい
and cherish myself above all.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I won't endure unreasonable things.
“それが私”
"That's me."
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cunning.
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying life.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for trying hard.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for my high girlish charm.
ムカついしちゃうよね?ざまぁw
Does it piss you off? Too bad!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
この時代生きててごめん
Sorry for living in this era.
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out.
意識しちゃうよね?ごめん
You notice it, don't you? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
自分磨きしてごめん
Sorry for polishing myself.
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for acting coquette.
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for captivating you.
ムカついしちゃうでしょ?ざまぁw
Does it piss you off? Too bad!
趣味の違い 変わり者と
Different hobbies, called an eccentric,
バカにされても 曲げたくない
even if mocked, I won't bend.
怖くもないんだからね
I'm not afraid at all.
自分の味方は自分でありたい 一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to be my own ally and cherish myself most.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I won't endure unreasonable things.
それが私
That's me.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cunning.
気になっちゃうよね?ごめん
Does it bother you? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for trying hard.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for my high girlish charm.
ムカついしちゃうよね?ざまぁw
Does it piss you off? Too bad!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cunning.
気になっちゃうよね?ごめん
Does it bother you? Sorry.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for trying hard.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for my high girlish charm.
私たちが私の事を愛して
I love myself,
何が悪いのか? 嫉妬でしょうか?
what's wrong with that? You just jealous?
痛いこととか変わってるとか
They say I'm cringey and odd,
届きませんね。そのリプライ
but I'm not listening to those replies.
大好きなお洋服 大好きなお化粧で
With my favorite clothes and favorite makeup on,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて お出かけしよう
with my iconic half-twintails curled, I'll go out.
日傘持って ぼっちだって
With my parasol, I'm alone, but
幸せだもん!
I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
生まれきてきちゃってごめん
sorry that I was born.
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry that I'm calculatingly cute,
気になっちゃうよね?ごめん
sorry that you can't ignore me.
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute,
努力しちゃっててごめん
sorry for working hard on myself.
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious,
女子力高くてごめん
sorry for being a girly girl.
ムカついちゃうよね?ざまぁw
It annoys you, right? You deserve it!
ほらゲームや壺男 弱音を吐いていたこよりを
Watching over Koyori, who vented her frustrations playing games,
見守って下さった思い出とともに 歌います
we will sing along with those memories.
路地裏の真ん中で 慣れない景色と好かない匂いに私は覆われて
In the middle of a back alley, covered by unfamiliar scenery and unscented smells,
染まっていくんでしょう 私は臆病で
I'm probably getting tainted, being as timid as I am.
知らないことには手を付けず 誰かがやってきて 毒味をするまで待っていた
I don't touch what I don't know, waiting for someone else to test it for poison.
ヨワネハキ
[Song: Yowanehaki]
私は強がりで 知らないことには手を付けず 誰かがやってきて
I put up a front, not touching what I don't know, waiting for someone else
毒見をするまで待っていた することは単純で マニュアル通りの生活を
to test it for poison. Doing things simply, living life by the manual,
来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
passing each day monotonously.
そういやそういやさ 昨日の私もこうだった
Oh yeah, oh yeah, yesterday was just like this.
そういやそういやさ
Oh yeah, oh yeah.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow person venting weak sounds.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます 絡まれたくないからさ
I'll stop taking a step forward, 'cause I don't want any trouble.
描いた理想像に現実味がないから近づけないように生きときます
Since my ideal image has no realism, I'll live keeping my distance.
明日も同じように過ごしときます
I'll spend tomorrow just the same.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow person venting weak sounds,
一歩前に出るのはやめときます 絡まれたくないからさ
I'll stop taking a step forward, 'cause I don't want any trouble.
描いた理想像に現実味がないから近づけないように生きときます
Since my ideal image has no realism, I'll live keeping my distance.
明日も同じように過ごしときます
I'll spend tomorrow just the same.
路地裏の真ん中で いつもの夕息を薄目で眺めて
In the middle of a back alley, gazing at the usual evening breath through squinted eyes,
胸の中で呟いた 「いつまで続くんだろう」
I muttered inside my chest, "How long will this last?"
そういやそういやさ 昨日の夕飯これだった
Oh yeah, oh yeah, yesterday's dinner was this.
そういやそういやさ 懦病で切りが悪いです
Oh yeah, oh yeah, I'm cowardly and clumsy.
意気地無し人間です 一歩後ろに下がって逃げときます
I'm a spineless person, stepping back and running away,
目立ちたくなんかないからさ 描いた理想像に現実味がないから
'cause I don't want to stand out. Since my ideal image has no realism,
近づけないように生きときます 明日も同じように過ごしときます
I'll live keeping my distance and spend tomorrow just the same.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow person venting weak sounds,
一歩前に出るのはやめときます
I'll stop taking a step forward.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm a shallow person venting weak sounds,
一歩前に出るのはやめときます 絡まれたくないからさ
I'll stop taking a step forward, 'cause I don't want any trouble.
ため息ばかりでさ 吸う息足りないの
It's all sighs, not enough breath to inhale.
きっと そう上手くはいかないけどさ 試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
I'm sure it won't go well, but let's try living properly.
解散だー！！
Dissolved again!!
何度も解散しました
We've disbanded so many times,
わけがわからないよ
I have no idea why!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promises we exchanged,
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to confirm.
押し寄せた闇振り払って進むよ
I will shake off the overwhelming darkness to move forward.
コネクト
[Song: Connect]
いつに なったらなくした未来を 私ここでまた見ることができるの?
When will I ever be able to see the lost future from here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を何度も裂いてこの世界歩んでいこう
Let's move forward by shattering the overflowing shadows of anxiety.
とめどなく刻まれた時は今始まり告げ変わらない思いをのせ閉じられた扉開けよう
Time now begins to tick away, let's open the closed door.
目覚めた心は走り出した未来を描くため難しい道で立ち止まっても
My heart awakes to depict the future, even if I halt on a tough road.
空はきれいな青さでいつも待っていてくれるから怖くない
The beautiful blue sky always waits for me, so I'm not afraid.
もう何があっても挫けない
I won't be disheartened no matter what.
振り返れば仲間がいて気がつけば優しく包まれてた
Looking back, my friends were there, gently wrapping around me.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で唯一信じられるここが救いだった
In a distorted world, this place I can believe in was my salvation.
目覚めた心は走り出した 未来をめがけて
With my awakened heart, I started running toward the future
難しい道で 立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さで いつも待っていてくれる
The sky, in its beautiful blue, is always waiting for me,
だから怖くない もう何があっても 挫けない
So I'm not afraid. No matter what happens, I won't give up.
解散だー！！
[Dissolution!!]
振り返れば 仲間がいて
When I looked back, my friends were there,
気づけば 優しく 包まれていた
Before I knew it, I was enveloped in their kindness.
何もかもが 歪んだ 世界で
In a world where everything was distorted,
唯一信じられる ここが救いだった
This was the only place I could believe in, my salvation.
喜びも 悲しみも
Joy and sadness alike,
分け合えば 強まる想い
Feelings grow stronger when shared.
この声が 届くのなら
If this voice can reach you,
きっと奇跡は 起こせるだろう
I'm sure we can work a miracle.
交わした約束 忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made,
目を閉じ 確かめる
I close my eyes and confirm it.
押し寄せた闇 振り払って 進むよ
Pushing aside the surging darkness, I'll move forward.
どんなに大きな 壁があっても
No matter how big the wall in our way,
超えてみせるから きっと
I will surely overcome it.
壊れた 世界で 彷徨っては
Wandering in a broken world,
私は 引き寄せられるように 辿り着いた
I arrived as if drawn in.
目覚めた心は 走り出した
With my awakened heart, I started running
未来をめがけて 難しい道で
Toward the future, on a difficult path,
立ち止まっても 空はきれいな青さで
Even if I stop, the sky is a beautiful blue,
いつも待っていてくれる
Always waiting for me.
だから怖くない もう何があっても
So I'm not afraid, no matter what happens,
挫けない ずっと明日待って
I won't give up, always waiting for tomorrow.
解散だー！！
[Dissolution!!]
ああ楽しもうよ シーソー 揺らす度
Ah, let's enjoy the seesaw, every time it swings,
受け取った不安定な居場所が浮くんだ
My unstable footing floats up from what I received.
エゴイスティック・シーソー
[Title: Egoistic Seesaw]
知らない事ばかり起き過ぎたね
Too many unfamiliar things have happened, haven't they?
目まぐるしく生きてたら それはそれで当然か
Living at such a dizzying pace, I suppose that's only natural.
当たりの入ってないその運試し
Trying my luck with no winning tickets in sight,
叫んで唇を噛んで 全てひっくり返したい
I scream, bite my lip, and want to turn everything upside down.
折角だし事後報告で エゴイスティックに
Since we're at it, I'll report it afterwards, egoistically,
騒ぎすぎ限界で痛いなら 労って
If I'm in pain from making too much noise, comfort me.
世界までの招待 頂戴
Give me an invitation to the world!
ああ楽しもうよ シーソー 揺らす度
Ah, let's enjoy the seesaw, every time it swings,
受け取った不安定な居場所が浮くんだ
My unstable footing floats up from what I received.
落ちた傷は舐めて貰えたら
If someone would lick the wounds I fell with,
後悔のないよう最後まで 生き急ごう
Let's live hastily till the very end with no regrets.
値札の付いてない僕等のゲーム
Our game without price tags.
抗って来たけれど
Though we've resisted up until now,
今は今で大変か
things are tough right now too.
模範にならない この遊び方
This way of playing sets no example,
飽きず 報われるなんて 考えず無邪気に
playing innocently without thinking of rewards or getting bored.
結局 ただ笑えたなら それでよかった
In the end, if we could just smile, that was enough.
ずっと 察せない 鈍感さ拾ったら
Picking up an oblivious insensitivity we could never quite grasp,
つなぐくらい しちゃうくらい はしゃいでしまおう
let's get so carried away we might even hold hands.
たまに見かける進化を追って
Chasing the evolution we occasionally see,
急ぎ転べば尻尾挟む
rushing in, we trip and get our tails caught.
委ねられないラインを 無我夢中で越えて前へ
Crossing lines we can't entrust to anyone, rushing ahead in a trance,
理想への招待状 頂戴
give me the invitation to our ideal!
一生 あぁ楽しもうよシーソー
A lifetime—ah, let's enjoy this seesaw,
壊すほど目一杯 戸惑って居場所を探した
struggling with all our might until it breaks, searching for our place.
落ちた傷は日常なんてさ
The scars we've fallen into are just everyday life,
後悔のないよう 最後まで生き急ごう
so let's live in a rush till the very end with no regrets.
やりたいこと成して 楽しい 手を振ってらしくいたい 苦しいなんて嫌だ
Achieving what we want, happily waving, wanting to be true to ourselves—suffering is the worst.
真っすぐなり振り構わず 網羅したい 我儘な夢もっと謳歌しよう
Straight ahead, without caring about appearances, we want to encompass all our selfish dreams even more!
はいということで、怒涛のゲストコーナーからその曲でしたが
So, that was the song from the whirlwind guest corner!
みんな何の曲ってなってたね！
Everyone was wondering what song that was!
実はこの曲はこよからのサプライズプレゼントです！
Actually, this song is a surprise present from me!
今の曲はなんと4曲目のオリジナル曲なんですよ！いぇーい！
That song was actually my 4th original song! Yay!
昨日のお誕生日カウントダウン配信で3曲目のオリジナル曲も発表しているので
Since I announced my 3rd original song in yesterday's birthday countdown stream,
まさかもう一曲あるとは思っていなかったんじゃないですかー？
you probably didn't think there'd be yet another song, right?
実はこの曲は、渡辺翔さんに作っていただきました！
Actually, this song was written by Sho Watanabe!
この曲「エゴスティック・シーソー」はライブのすぐ後にMVがプレミア公開されます！
The MV for "Egoistic Seesaw" will premiere right after this live!
概要欄にもURLを追加しますのでぜひチェックしてくださいね！
I'll add the URL in the description box, so please check it out!
このあとはまだまだ怒涛のライブコーナーです！2つ目のゲストパートもあります！
After this, we still have the whirlwind live corner and a second guest part!
それではステージを移動します！いくよー！
Now, let's move the stage! Here we go!
時を刻む唄 作詞・作曲：麻枝准
[Song: Toki o Kizamu Uta / Lyrics & Music: Jun Maeda]
落ちていく砂時計ばかり見てるよ
I just watch as the hourglass continues to fall.
さかさまにすればほらまた始まるよ
When I turn it upside down, look, it starts over.
刻んだだけ進む時間に
In this time that ticks away as it passes,
いつか僕も入れるかな
I wonder if I'll ever be able to enter too.
きみだけが過ぎ去った坂の途中は あたたかな日だまりがいくつもできてた
On the slope where only you passed by, many warm sunny spots had formed.
僕ひとりがここで優しい
Here, I alone am gentle,
温かさを思い返してる
recalling that warmth.
きみだけを きみだけを好きでいたよ
You alone, you alone, I loved you.
風で目が滲んで遠くなるよ
My eyes blur with the wind and grow distant.
遠くなるよ
Growing distant...
It's getting distant...
いつまでも 覚えてる
Forever and ever, I'll remember
なにもかもが変わっても
Even if everything changes,
ひとつだけ ありふれたものだけど
just one thing, though it's mundane,
見せてやる 輝びに満ちたそのひとつだけ
I'll show you that one radiant thing.
いつまでも いつまでも 守ってゆく
Forever and ever, I will protect it.
肌寒い日が続く もう春なのに
Chilly days continue, even though it's spring,
目覚まし時計より早く起きた朝
waking up earlier than the alarm clock.
三人分の朝ご飯を作るきみが
You, making breakfast for three people,
そこに立っている
are standing right there.
きみだけが きみだけが
Only you, only you
そばにいないよ
aren't by my side.
昨日まで すぐそばで 僕をみてたよ
Until yesterday, right beside me, you were looking at me.
きみだけを 好きでいたよ
It's only you that I loved.
きみだけと 歌う唄だよ
It's the song I sing only with you.
僕たちの 刻んだ時だよ
It's the time we carved together.
片方だけ続くなんて 僕はいやだよ
Continuing to be just one-sided... I hate that.
いつまでも 覚えている
I'll always remember.
いつまでも 覚えてる この町が変わっても
I'll always remember, even if this town changes,
どれだけの悲しみと出会うことになっても
no matter how much sorrow I meet.
さあ行くよ 歩き出す 坂の道を
Come on, let's go, walking up the hill road.
謳歌、いつもの様に 過ぎる日々にあくびが出る
Ah, like every day, passing days make me yawn.
ざんざめく夜、越え、今日も
Crossing the noisy night, today too,
渋谷の街に朝が降る
morning falls upon the streets of Shibuya.
どこか虚しいような そんな気持ち つまらないな
Somehow empty feelings, how boring...
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ
but that's fine, that's just how it is.
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ
Unknowingly hiding it, let your true voice resonate,
ほら見ないふりしていても 確実にそこにある
hey, even if you pretend not to see it, it's there.
感じたままに描く 自分でもらったその色で
Drawing as I felt, with the color I chose myself,
眠い空気纏う朝に 訪れた青い世界
in a morning in drowsy air, a blue world arrived.
好きなものを好きだと言う 怖くて仕方ないけど
Saying I like what I like, though terrified,
本当の自分に出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I met my true self.
鳴呼、手を伸ばせば
Ah, if I reach out my hand,
伸ばすほどに 遠くへゆく
the further I reach, the further away it gets.
思うようにいかない、今日も
Things don't go the way I want, even today,
また慌ただしくもがいてる
struggling in a flurry once again.
悔しい気持ちもただ
These frustrating feelings
情けなくて 涙が出る
are just pathetic, and tears fall.
踏み込むほど 苦しくなる
The deeper I step, the more painful it gets,
痛くもなる
and the more it hurts too.
感じたままに進む
Moving forward just as I felt,
自分で選んだこの道を
on this path I chose myself.
重いまぶた擦る夜に
In a night rubbing heavy eyelids,
しがみついた青い誓い
a blue oath I clung to.
好きなことを続けること
Continuing to do what I love
それは「楽しい」だけじゃない
isn't just "fun".
本当にできる？ 不安になるけど
Can I really do it? Though I get anxious,
何枚でも ほら何枚でも 自信がないから
no matter how many times, see, since I lack confidence,
描いてきたんだよ
I've been drawing all along.
何回でも ほら何回でも 積み上げてきたことが武器になる
No matter how many times, what I've piled up becomes a weapon.
周りを見ったって 誰と比べたって 僕にしかできないことはなんだ
Looking around, comparing with anyone, what is the thing only I can do?
今でも自信なんかない それでも
Even now I have no confidence, even so,
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた想い
feelings I've never felt, thoughts I was unaware of,
あの日踏み出して 初めて感じたこの痛みも全部
all this pain I felt for the first time stepping out that day.
好きなものと向き合うことで
By facing what I love,
触れたまだ小さな光
a small light I touched—
大丈夫、行こう あとは楽しむだけだ
it's okay, let's go, all that's left is to enjoy it.
全てを賭けて描く
Drawing with everything on the line,
自分にしか出せない色で
with colors only I can bring out.
朝も夜も走り続け 見つけ出した青い光
Running through morning and night, the blue light I found.
好きなものと向き合うこと
Facing what I love,
今だって怖いことだけど もう今はあの日の透明な僕じゃない
even now it's scary, but now I'm no longer the transparent me of that day.
ありのままのかけがえのない僕だ
I am my irreplaceable, true self.
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を響かせてよ
Let the true voice I unconsciously hid echo out.
ほら 見ないふりしていても 確かにそこにあるよ
Look, even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely right there.
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を響かせてよ
Let the true voice I unconsciously hid echo out.
さあ 見ないふりしていても 確かにあるよ 君の中に
Come on, even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely inside you.
風に吹かれて 誰も気づかぬよう
Blown by the wind, so that no one notices,
区別がつかない モノクロの世界
a monochrome world where distinction can't be made.
色を足しても 何も見えなくて
Even adding color, nothing could be seen,
まるで私は 息を止めていた
it was as if I had stopped breathing.
もういいよ 遠くても 叶えたい 私は
That's enough, even if it's far, I want to make it come true.
こんな世界 想いも 抱きしめていたいのについに
Even though I wanted to embrace my feelings in this world,
夢のキャンバスに 居続ける意味は この胸に 輝いている ストーリー
the meaning of staying on the dream's canvas is shining in my heart, a story.
与えることに 意味などないけど
Though there's no meaning in giving,
拾い集めた カケラ失うの？
will I lose the fragments I picked up?
そして夜は その冷たさを 溶かして 手を伸ばした
And the night melted that coldness and reached out a hand.
もういいよ 遠くても 届けたい 私は
That's enough, even if it's far, I want to reach it.
受け止めてく
Catching them,
涙も
even my tears—
抱きしめていたいのにな
I wanted to hold them close...
夢のキャンバスに
On the canvas of my dreams,
心込めるのは
pouring my heart into it—
この空に 描きだしてく
painting it across this sky,
ストーリー
a story...
そして 夜はその冷たさを 溶かして
And then, melting the chill of the night,
手を伸ばした
I reached out my hand.
もういいの 遠くても
It's alright, even if it's far,
叶いたい 私の
I want to make my dream come true—
こんな世界 想いも言葉で包んだ
wrapping this world and my feelings in words.
夢のキャンバスに 色を足してゆく
Adding colors to the canvas of my dreams,
この胸に 今輝いて
shining brightly within my heart right now.
強くなくてもいい
It's okay not to be strong,
壊れかけてもいい
it's okay to start falling apart.
この心は 永遠に羽ばたいて
May this heart soar forever,
響くように 塗り替えていく
repainting the world to resonate—
Ｐａｌｅｔｔｅ
Palette.
ドッキリ大成功☆
Prank successfully pulled off!
悪戯に君をずっと見ていた訳じゃない
It's not like I've just been playfully watching you all this time.
僕の考えを当ててごらんよ
Try guessing what's on my mind!
些細な仕草 視線 瞬き
Subtle gestures, gazes, blinking—
君はもう掌に
you're already in the palm of my hand.
剥き出しのtrapなんてかかる訳ないわ
There's no way I'd fall for some bare trap.
甘い言葉にも惑わされない
Nor will I be swayed by sweet words.
心の奥の奥の奥まで見透しちゃうよ
I'll see right through to the very depths of your heart!
Looking thinking touching feeling
Why you know?
I know it
Looking thinking touching feeling
Understand?
Meaning meaning of love Are you ready?
自覚ないでしょうね 思い通りに
You probably don't even realize you're being
君は動かされている事！
manipulated just as planned!
単純じゃないの 駆け引きのhintを
Don't overlook all the hints
全て見落とさないで
in our complex game of push-and-pull.
加速してく 二人の鼓動
Our accelerating heartbeats...
心理戦は次のstageへ
This mind game moves to the next stage.
虚ろなその目に 私はどう映るの
How do I reflect in those hollow eyes of yours?
とても煌びやかで まるでシンデレラ
So dazzling, just like Cinderella.
突き刺す視線 ゾクと感じて 君に余裕見せつけて
Feeling your piercing gaze, showing you my composure,
あからさま過ぎて お腹がよじるよ 既に君はもう出来上がってる
it's so blatant it makes my stomach hurt—you're already completely wrapped around my finger!
Looking thinking touching feeling
Why you know?
I know it
Looking thinking touching feeling
Understand?
Meaning meaning of love Are you ready?
唯一無二のjoker 手にするために
To get my hands on the one and only joker,
欲望を晒け出してるのさ
I'm laying my desires bare!
離れていく世界のlogicを 君は楽しめるかな
Can you enjoy the logic of a drifting world?
重要なkeyword 全てsecret
Crucial keywords, all a secret.
後戻りはできないステージへ
To a stage of no return.
気付いているでしょ ここにいる意味さえ
You must realize the very meaning of being here.
切り札はそれぞれお互いの手札に
Our trumps are in each other's hands.
悪戯に君をずっと見ていた訳じゃない
It's not like I've been teasingly
watching you all along.
僕の考えを見てごらんよ
Just look at what I'm thinking!
些細な仕草 視線 瞬き 君はもう掌に
You're already in the palm of my hand.
剥き出しのtrapなんかかからないわ
There's no way I'd fall for a trap,
甘い言葉にも惑わされないわ
nor be swayed by sweet words.
心の奥の奥の奥まで見透かしてしまうよ
I see straight into your heart!
(looking thinking touching feeling,)
why you know？
why you know?
(looking thinking touching feeling,)
君は動かされている事！
You're being manipulated!
単純じゃないのかけ引きのhintを全て見落とさないで
It's not that simple, don't miss the hints.
加速してく二人の鼓動 心理戦は次のstageへ
Our heartbeats accelerate into the next stage.
虚ろなその目に私はどう映るのか
How do I look in those hollow eyes?
とても艶やかでまるでcinderella
So glamorous, just like Cinderella.
突き刺す視線ゾクンと感じて
Feeling the piercing gaze give me chills.
真実線は次のステージへ
Moving to the next stage...
おツボネ宝鐘先パイと
Senior Advisor Houshou Marine
新人白衣さん。
and newcomer Hakui Koyori.
マリン先パイ自作ゲームなどの思い出とともに、
With many memories of indie games,
頭ピンク組の二人で歌います。
they sing together as the pink-haired duo!
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危なげな dangerous marine smell
A box hiding allure, a dangerous marine smell.
(kore aketara kimi-tachi ni nante itte agerubeki kanaa...?)
(When you open this, what should I say...?)
("o-takara yori miryoku tekiな"mono" mitsuke chatta...?)
("Did you find something more attractive than treasure...?")
誘うガネットの赤 それは私
The enticing gannet red, that is me.
艶が溢れ漂う香りをどうか怪しまないで
Please don't fear this overflowing scent.
ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたくない?
Don't you want to catch the runaway captain?
you're gonna get the treasure maybe tasting me
私の甘さが欲しいのでしょう
You want my sweetness, don't you?
秘宝の鍵を優しく刺して
Gently insert the key to the treasure.
宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
Open the vault door quickly!
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘いため息のtease
Your impatient hand—a sweet sigh of tease.
純紅のバラがしおれる前に we will sail the seven seas
Before the deep red rose withers, we will sail.
summer sun smiling with glee shining ocean of marine
Summer sun smiling with glee, shining ocean.
now please grant my dearest dream open up this box open it right now or i will scream
Open up this box or I will scream!
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa!!!!!!!
キミたちももう我慢できなくなってる?
Can you guys not hold back anymore?
you're gonna own the pleasure maybe love of me?
金銀財宝はした金でしょ
Gold, silver, and treasures are mere pocket change.
しわしわになっちゃう 誰か助けて
I'll end up all wrinkled up, someone help!
分かってるんだわ渇望だから今すぐ開けてよ 宝庫
I know it's a craving, open the vault!
貴方を待つガネット キミたちも開けて~~!!
The gannet waiting for you... open it up!!
みみせーさーせーぶし！ 7つの大会を
Mimisasesasebushi! Seven tournaments!
さーわーさー smiling with glee
Sawasawa smiling with glee!
またねにかけすすんで シャイニーオーシャンマリン
Stepping forward to shiny ocean marine.
まだ手はわずからない なに想像してんの
Don't get your hands dirty, what are you imagining?
open up this box open it right now i will scream
Open up this box, open it right now!
さむのさだめ さわさわ smiling with glee またね かけすすんで シャイニーオーシャンマリン
Sawasawa smiling with glee, shiny ocean marine.
まだ手はわずからない なに想像してんの 開けろ！！
Open it up!!
Maybe love me
私のすべてを手に入れて
take all of me into your hands.
❤Ahoy❤
Ahoy!
ねえ開けたら君たちになんて言ってあげようかな...?
Hey, what should I say to you guys if you open this...?
探してたのはせ・ん・ち・ょ・お? ううん…
What I was looking for was Se-n-chou? Nah...
あんそんなにがっついちゃダメだぞ❤
Hey, don't get so greedy over it❤
お宝より魅力的な”モノ”見つけちゃった…? いいじゃない❤
Did you find something even more charming than treasure...? Isn't that nice❤
誘うガーネットの赤
Enticing garnet red,
極上の海賊の秘宝
the ultimate pirate treasure.
それは私
That is me,
艶が溢れ漏れる香りをどうか怯えないで
so please don't be afraid of this alluring scent.
開けてみて
Open it up...
Sexy世界一 Superピチピチ ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたくない?
The sexiest in the world, super perky, don't you want to catch the captain?
You’re gonna get the treasure Maybe tasting me
You're gonna get the treasure, maybe tasting me,
私の甘さが欲しいでしょう
you want my sweetness, don't you?
秘宝の鍵を優しく刺して
Gently insert the key to the treasure,
宝庫の扉マジで早く開けて
and open the vault door really quickly.
たくさんの思い出を巡るライブ、楽しんでいただけてますかーっ！
Are you enjoying the live stream filled with so many memories?!
たくさんのポチポチポチも、ありがとーーっ！
And thank you so much for all the constant cheers!
でもですね、思い出は振り返っているだけでは、先へは進めません！
But you know, just looking back at memories won't move us forward!
思い出とともにもっともっと素敵な未来へ歩んでいけるように、今日発表したばかりの3曲目のオリジナル曲を歌って踊らせてください！
To be able to walk towards an even more wonderful future together with our memories, please let me sing and dance to my 3rd original song I just announced today!
白衣こよりの自己紹介ソングです！いくよー！地上最大のQUESTIONっ！
It's Hakui Koyori's self-introduction song! Here we go! The Greatest QUESTION in History!
今（ゼッタイ）以上（史上）最大
Now (absolutely) more than ever (in history),
叶えましょう！ここより博衣こよりだよ、今日は人類最大の謎を証明していくよ！
let's make our greatest dreams come true! Today I'll prove humanity's greatest mystery!
探究心メラメラ抑えられないので
My inquisitive spirit is blazing and I can't hold it back,
博士号なのでヨユーです！こよはすのーです！すのー！
so since I have a doctorate, it's a breeze! That's Koyohasno! That's no!
またひとつ発見マヨネーズは飲み物です
Another discovery: mayonnaise is a drink!
カモンQ and A
Come on, Q and A!
あっちこっちほら巻き起こるドラマに体当たり…実践！
Over here, over there, diving headfirst into the drama unfolding... Execution!
感じてみなきゃ始まらない
If you don't feel it, nothing begins.
研究！(ゴーゴー！) 生成！(あんきー！) 共有！(成果！) で
Research! (Go! Go!) Generation! (Anki!) Sharing! (Results!) With...
Are you OK?
一緒にどんどん過ごしましょう
Let's spend more and more time together,
あなたと経験していくタイム
a time experiencing things with you.
全部の一夢そろえて証明完了-Q.E.D.-したってね また次がある
Gathering all our dreams, proof complete -Q.E.D.- Done that? There's always next time.
泣いて笑ってわおーん どんな日も永遠願いはスマイル
Crying, laughing, woof! No matter the day, our eternal wish is a smile,
その胸に芽生えて欲しいシアワセ
wanting happiness to sprout in your heart.
今（ゼッタイ）以上（史上）最大叶えましょう！
Now (absolutely) more than ever (in history), let's make our greatest dreams come true!
助手くんだち元気にしてる～？ ついてこなきゃこーだよ〜ん！
Assistants, are you doing well? If you don't follow, like this!
たまに足しかけ無いだけどなんか不思議じゃない？
Sometimes not putting our foot down, but isn't it kind of mysterious?
そんな疑問 ワン ツー スリー 集めちゃうわない？
Such questions, one, two, three, shouldn't we gather them up?
常にTry！ やだ Error?
Always try! Oh no, Error?
平気次はきっとFine！ もりだくさんなDay
It's fine, next time will definitely be Fine! A day full of things.
ピックアップした謎解きの向こう側に隠れた…命題！
The proposition hidden beyond the picked-up riddle!
見逃したらもったいない
It's a waste to miss it.
冒険！(ゴーゴー！) 想像！(あんきー！) 融合！(成果！) で
Adventure! (Go! Go!) Imagination! (Anki!) Fusion! (Results!) With...
Are you OK?
いそげーっ！ いっせーのせっ！
Hurry! Ready, set!
未来どんどん進めましょう 僕らに限界はないから
Let's move further and further into the future, because there are no limits for us.
何か一つ叶えてしまっても大丈夫 ほら次がある 飛んで跳ねてわおーん
Even if one dream comes true, it's okay, look, there's a next one. Jump and bounce, woof!
いつだって行動原理はね その胸に満杯届けてしまいたい
Our principle of action always is to deliver it fully into that chest.
ヨロコビのために！ はい！はい！はい！わー！
For the sake of joy! Yes! Yes! Yes! Wow!
アイムコヨテー！ かわいいでーす とや！
I'm Koyote! We're so cute, right!
いつもどっちに行ったら正解なのかは
Knowing which way is always the correct one...
実はとっても難しいけれど だからこそです 迷った時には
...is actually very difficult, but precisely because of that, when you're lost,
笑顔だけを見つめます
just gaze only at smiles.
あっちこっちほら巻き起こる ドラマに体当たり…実践！
Over here, over there, diving headfirst into the drama unfolding... Execution!
感じて そしてはじめましょう
Feel it, and let's begin.
研究！(ゴーゴー！) 生成！(あんきー！) 共有！(成果！) で
Research! (Go! Go!) Generation! (Anki!) Sharing! (Results!) With...
Are you OK?
一緒にどんどん過ごしましょう あなたと経験していくタイム
Let's spend more and more time together, a time experiencing things with you.
全部の一夢そろえて証明完了-Q.E.D.-したってね また次がある
Gathering all our dreams, proof complete -Q.E.D.- Done that? There's always next time.
泣いて 笑ってわおーん
Cry, laugh, awooo!
どんな日も永遠願いはスマイル
No matter the day, my eternal wish is a smile.
その胸に芽生えて欲しい シアワセ
I want happiness to blossom in your heart.
今（ゼッタイ）以上（史上）最大（最高）のテーマ
Now, more than ever, the greatest theme!
さあ（さあ）もっと（ずっと）Happy 叶えましょう！
Come on, let's make more and more happy come true!
助手くんたち準備はいいですか？ まだまだたくさん証明していくからね〜！
Assistants, are you ready? I'm going to prove a lot more!
あっぱれ！
Splendid!
はーい！ということで、博衣こより生誕ライブ2023 メモリーズ、お楽しみいただきありがとうございました！
Hi there! Thank you so much for enjoying Hakui Koyori's Birthday Live 2023 Memories!
このあとのエンディングでゲストの皆さんとのプチトークもありますので最後まで見ていってくださいね！
There will be a mini-talk with our guests in the ending after this, so please watch until the end!
ということで、ここで大事なお知らせをさせてください。
And now, please let me make a very important announcement.
まず一つ目は、今歌った新曲「史上最大のQUESTION！」は、すでに本日の0時からデジタル配信開始されております！
First, the new song we just sang, "Shijyo Saidai no QUESTION!", is already available for digital streaming starting at midnight today!
概要欄から飛べますので、ぜひさっきのエゴイスティックシーソーと合わせてゲットしてください！
You can access it from the description box, so please grab it along with "Egoistic Seesaw"!
そして、二つめぇ！博衣こより誕生日グッズ2023が発売されますー！一つ目はお待たせいたしました！ラバーマット＆カードスリーブのセット！
And second! Hakui Koyori's Birthday Goods 2023 are on sale! First, thank you for waiting! The rubber mat and card sleeve set!
イラストは、あの、こよの推しのイラストなども手掛けていらっしゃるきりさき先生にお描きいただきました！
The illustration was drawn by Kirisaki-sensei, who has also worked on illustrations of Koyori's oshi!
カードゲーム好きとしては絶対に欲しかったスリーブも付けちゃったよ！お気に入りのカードを入れてください！
As a card game lover, I even added sleeves I definitely wanted! Put your favorite cards in them!
そして、ライブの思い出を飾れるキャンバスボード！イラストは北田藻先生描き下ろしです！すごくエモモで元気あふれる1枚に仕上げていただきました！
And, a canvas board to display your live memories! Illustrated exclusively by Kitada M-sensei! They finished it into a super emotional and energetic piece!
さらに！お待たせしました！助手くん証明書ーー！
Furthermore! Thanks for waiting! Assistant-kun Certificate!
こよりラボの社員証みたいなめっちゃしっかりした材質の証明書になっています！あなただけのナンバリング入りで名前もかけちゃう！
It's a certificate made of super solid material like an ID card for Koyori Lab! It features your own numbering and you can even write your name!
裏面はお財布に入れたりしてちらっと見えた時にハッピーになれるキリサキ先生の描き下ろしイラスト入りでこよの手書きメッセージとサインも入ってますよ！
The back features an original illustration by Kirisaki-sensei that makes you happy when it peeks out of your wallet, along with my handwritten message and signature!
そして、お誕生日を一緒に過ごせるシチュエーションボイスも販売します！全部セットにはなんと特典がふたつ！
And, we are also selling situation voice packs to spend your birthday together! The full set includes two special bonuses!
一つ目は博衣こよりオリジナルのサイン入りのカードです！限定数でごめんね！直筆サインを入れさせていただきます！みんなに行き渡るくらいにはかく予定なんですけどお早めにお願いします！
First is an original card with Hakui Koyori's signature! Sorry, it's in limited quantities! I'll put my autographed signature on them. I plan to make enough for everyone, but please get yours early!
二つ目はこよが逆に助手くんのお誕生日をお祝いしちゃうASMRボイス！こよも助手くんのことお祝いしたかったんだ〜！ゲットして置いて自分の誕生日に聞いてくださいね！
Second is an ASMR voice where Koyori celebrates assistant-kun's birthday instead! Koyori wanted to celebrate assistant-kun too! Grab it and listen to it on your birthday!
以上、お知らせでした！生誕祭来てくれてありがと！
That's all for the announcements! Thank you for coming to my birthday festival!
いつもたくさんの思い出をありがとう！助手くん、大好きだよーー！
Thank you always for so many memories! Assistant-kun, I love you so much!
こより、お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！イェーイ！
Koyori, happy birthday! Thank you! Yay!
この3人でこのサトラシ踊れてよかった！本当こよも嬉しかったです！
I'm so glad we could dance this Satorashi with these three! I was really happy too, Koyo!
すごいなんかさ、声めっちゃ合ってたよね！合ってた合ってただったけど、よかったですよね！
It's amazing how well our voices matched! They really matched, though it just started, it was great right?
いやほんともっともっとこの3人でね、またなんかやるしかない！歌ったり踊ったりしましょう！
Truly, the three of us just have to do something again! Let's sing and dance!
メルちゃん、ノエル先輩、お風呂含めいっぱい遊んでくれてありがとうございます！
Mel-chan, Noel-senpai, thank you so much for playing with me a lot including the bath!
こよちゃん、また一緒にお風呂入ろうね！たーっぷり！
Koyo-chan, let's take a bath together again! Plenty!
汗かいたし今入っちゃおっか？え、いいですか？えー！ぐにゅー！
We worked up a sweat, so shall we jump right in now? Eh, is that okay? Eh! Squish!
助手先輩、つぼじ、ふぶき先輩、ほら、見守りありがとうございます！
Joushu-senpai, Tsuboji, Fubuki-senpai, look, thank you for watching over us!
次は金ツボだね！楽しみだな！おわりが入っても大丈夫だからこれからもほら、頑張って
Next is Gold Tsubo, right? I'm looking forward to it! Even if Owari gets in it's fine, so from now on look, do your best!
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
え、あ、ひっ…
Huh, ah, hih...
が、が、が、が、頑張ります！
I-I-I'll do my best!
へへ、頑張ろ、頑張ろ！
Hehe, let's do our best!
おっかゆー！
Okayu!
お誕生日おめでとうだー！
Happy birthday!
あー、ありがとうー！
Ah, thank you!
いやあ、デュエットライブは初めてだったけど、クロタンの愛が伝わってきたよ。
Yeah, it was my first duet live, and Kuro-tan's love really came through.
え、なんか、ライモニ見えてます？
Eh, like, is the live monitor visible?
こつ、こ、こつ、クロタン誕生日だぞ、おい！
H-Hey, Kuro-tan, it's your birthday, hey!
あ、誕生日おめでとう！じゃねえだろ、コヨルカイスー！
Ah, Happy birthday! isn't what you should say, Koyorukaisu!
なー、こうよ、これ、コヨルカイスー！
Hey, Koyoru, this is Koyorukaisu!
ねぇ、トワ様さぁ、
Hey, Towa-sama,
あのー、こういう外様って、まぶってことでいいですかねぇ？
um, for outsiders like this, is it alright to consider them close friends?
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
さすがにそろそろ？
Surely by now?
うん。
Yeah.
まぶでは…まぶで…しょう？
As close friends... close friends... right?
ないよねぇ？なのに今いい感じだったじゃん！
Not really, right? But things were going so well just now!
いやでも、ほらここでほら、まぶって言ってさ、
Well, but look, if I say we're close friends here,
これからさ、トワに絡むときにさ、「え、まぶでしょ？」の絡みができなくなるかなと思って。
I thought maybe I wouldn't be able to tease you later with 'Eh, aren't we close friends?' when interacting with Towa.
なるほど！そうそうそう！あ、いっぱい小宵にこれからも絡んでほしいってことですね！
I see! Exactly! Ah, so you want Koyoi to keep interacting with you a lot from now on!
あ、今日はお互いめでたいね！
Ah, today we're both celebrating!
マリーさん！
Marine-san!
開けてもらえなかったね！
You couldn't get it opened, huh!
いや本当にそうですよ！あれ、小宵１人だったら開けてもらえたかな？
Seriously, yeah! If it was just Koyoi alone, I wonder if she would've opened it for us?
はあ！？はあ！？まり１人だったら、はあ、まり１人だったら開けてもらえたのにさ！
Huh?! Huh?! If it was just Marine alone, huh, if it was just Marine alone, she would've opened it for us!
この曲、あの開けてもらえてないじゃないですか、１人で歌って…さ、さすがにさ、負けました！敗者されてしまいました！ずなー！
This song, didn't she not get it opened for her, singing alone... w-well, you know, we lost! We ended up defeated! Zunaaa!
ずなー！まあでも、こんなにね、すんごい財宝あれば、２人ぼっちでも楽しいっすよね！
Zunaaa! Well, but, with such amazing treasure here, even being all alone together is fun, right?
確かに！そうだよね、小宵はお誕生日おめでとう！
True! That's right, Happy Birthday, Koyori!
あ、ここで暮らそう！一緒に！ずっと一緒だよ！いぇーい！わいわい！
Ah, let's live here! Together! We'll be together forever! Yay! Yay!
生誕祭LIVE！きてくれてありがとう！みんなにお祝いしてもらって最高の誕生日になったよ(≧∇≦)
Thank you for coming to the Birthday Live! Celebrating with everyone made it the best birthday ever!
ハッシュタグで感想書いてくれたら嬉しいな♡みにいくね！！
I'd be so happy if you share your thoughts with the hashtag! I'll go check them out!!
また1年いっしょに楽しんで、来年もこの場所で会おう！！
Let's enjoy another year together and meet again in this place next year!!
2023.3.15 博衣こより
March 15, 2023 - Hakui Koyori